Tufts Family Collection MS050
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Legal and financial records, 1791 -- 2009; MS050.003; .9 Linear Feet
  - Brickyard and tannery journal, 1817 -- 1850; MS050.003.007.00009 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Journal book, folio, full leather, 354pp. plus. Kept in a fine clerical hand. Good condition, dampstaining of laid paper near covers. Completely filled. Alphabetical index at front of 227 names, including John Augustus (1785-1859), Boston philanthropist and friend of the poor; Samuel Appleton (1766-1853), Boston merchant; and many others. Fifteen continuous years of accounts, 1817-1832, with a few accounts to 1850 added, not part of the numbering. Personal and business accounts for leather soles, brick sales, labor. Sold leather to the State prison.
  - Brickyard account book, 1801 -- 1807; MS050.003.007.00010 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Account-book, square 8vo boards. 172pp. accounts (completely filled). Heavily worn, not affecting text. Dampstaining very occasionally impairs legibility. Six years of continuous records of sales of bricks to individuals and firms. Customers included W. Harrison Otis, Thomas [Green] Fessenden, and many ethers. Also hundreds of thousands of bricks were sold to Jonathan Hunnerwell in 1802 for his bank and home.
  - Brickyard account book, 1813 -- 1828; MS050.003.007.00011 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Account-book, sq. 8vo, l/4th leather, boards. 166pp. accounts (completely filled). Moderate-to-heavy wear, not affecting the text. Some dampstaining. "Thos. Pike's Team Book, May 18, 1807," appears on the first leaf and this account runs for 30pp., recording Pike's work for the Tufts, grinding bark, carting bricks, etc. All 1807. "Daniel Tufts' Brick Book" appears on blank page following Pike's accounts and runs 96pp. in clerical hand. Continuous accou.,ts for individuals and firt1S who did business with the company. Includes the account of Francis Amory, who purchased 288,750 bricks at $6.00 per 1,000. Summary of bricks manufactured: in 1818, 415,107; in 1819, 389,390. Bricks sold to the Manufacturers & Mechanics Bank, 1814; to the West Boston Society, 1814; etc. The last 40pp. are miscellaneous accounts, labor, raw materials, etc., of the period.
  - Tannery sales account book, 1804 -- 1840; MS050.003.007.00012 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Account-book, sq. 8vo boards. 174pp. accounts (completely filled). Very heavy wear to exterior, not affecting legibility and integrity of accounts. Dampstaining throughout. Titled "Sole leather account book 1804," it traces accounts for a thirty-six year period, 1804-1840. It is the family's sales-record of processed sole leather to hundreds of individuals and firms. A few wood accounts for the earliest period are also included at the back, as well as a few brick accounts scattered in.
  - Tufts, Daniel - cash receipts, circa 1840 -- 1860; MS050.003.008.00001; 2 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    Description from dealer: Miscellaneous lot of about 300 cash receipts to Daniel Tufts 2d., given in the 1840's and 1850's, for sundry personal items: wood, stone, taxes, pew rent, groceries, personal expenses. Many partially printed with fancy rules and devices. All sizes from 8vo to 16mo, on different shades and qualities of paper.
  - The Tufts Family Business Collection, 1797-1856 - documentation, circa 1978; MS050.003.008.00002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tufts, Peter and Hannah Tufts deed and correspondence, 1800 -- 2009; MS050.003.008.00003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Tufts, Peter; Annie Adams; and Joseph Tufts - will, photographs, and poetry, circa 1791 -- 1971; MS050.003.008.00004 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Subject files, 1840 -- 2013; MS050.004; .4 Linear Feet
  This series contains subject files transferred from the Vertical Files Collection (UA073). They contain correspondence, clippings, publications, and photographs relating to Tuft family members who were alumni, faculty, staff, or honorary degree recipients at Tufts University. The bulk of the material in this series date from 1976 to 1993. Files of faculty and staff in the vertical files often contain correspondence with the president and upper administration of Tufts.
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Tufts, Anne Blanchard, 1972 -- 1991; MS050.004.005.00089 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Charles, circa 1904 -- 1981; MS050.004.005.00090 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Charles and family photos and portraits, circa 1932 -- 1988; MS050.004.005.00091 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Cotton, circa 1962 -- 1993; MS050.004.005.00092 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Daniel - business collection purchase, 1978; MS050.004.005.00093 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Daniel A. B., circa 1981; MS050.004.005.00094 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Elizabeth V., 1976; MS050.004.005.00095 (Box 5)
  - Tufts family general, 1948 -- 1988; MS050.004.005.00096 (Box 5)
  - Tufts family history and genealogy, circa 1926 -- 1986; MS050.004.005.00097 (Box 5)
  - Tufts family manuscript, 1840 -- 1977; MS050.004.005.00098 (Box 5)
    This folder contains a copy of an Agreement of Sale for land to Tufts College dated 1856.
  - Tufts family printed matter, 1947 -- 1980; MS050.004.005.00099 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Francis, 1992; MS050.004.005.00100 (Box 5)
  - Tufts. Harry N., 1988; MS050.004.005.00101 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, James Walker, circa 1890 -- 2013; MS050.004.005.00102 (Box 5)
  - Tufts, Kingsley, 1993; MS050.004.005.00103 (Box 5)